okay let's do a meditation your any cell
phone off getting my god
all right relax your heads loosen up
your shoulders get a little smile right
so pulling your head is coming to the
movement relax your eyes I knew relax
you for her
and come to your breath
just focus on long snow exhales and
start to bring your mind inside
then in a diamond cutter search at the
next part we're going to study cebu d
ask how did you get your teachings when
you were telling studying from past
Buddhist then how did you get teachings
and Buddha says oh I made offerings to
many millions of Buddhas I made
offerings and then Camila Sheila master
kimora Sheila says do you want to know
what kind of offerings he made he says
what Buddha offered to his teachers to
request teachings and to get more
teachings was the offering of his
practice not not things so it's nice to
offer material things flowers food money
those aren't nice but the greatest
offering to your teachers is to try to
practice in Tibetan language is called
Guba and it means the word for practice
means child practice it means we're not
perfect we did some of us did a pretty
long retreat here the last two weeks we
try to meditate we try to be quiet and
we try to
follow the teaching about emptiness and
karma and of course we had many bad days
the weather was bad or something
problem happened in our retreat cottage
or the food then we didn't like too soon
or we ate too much food and we didn't
have enough food and it's not easy to be
doing retreat in a place which is empty
like this it's not like Berlin or Moscow
or Mexico City or Gyeongju it is hard
place wild place but very quiet place so
of course many things weren't perfect
but many of us came here from far far
away we spent a lot of money for us to
get here we took time from our families
from our work and we start for many
hours listening to ancient teachings
difficult teachings so all of us were
not perfect and we're not great Yogi's
but in this world
modern busy wechat world we are doing
our best to learn something new and to
make our minds better be
better people understand how to be
better people and we are we have some
intention some hope that we can help the
whole world so I would like to during
this meditation each person here start
with a few weeks or months ago when you
decided to come here you you made your
first payment or there's no teaching
further there's no charge for the
teaching but you had to reserve your
college you had to get everything ready
at work and family and ever since then
up to today this morning we've worked
really hard in a world where many people
don't care about these things you are
doing your best to follow the ancient
wisdom and the way of life of these
ancient wise people and so I'll be quiet
for a few minutes and I'd like you to
think about how much you charge during
this last few weeks how each thing you
did oh I bought the airplane ticket I
talked to my job or I you know walked to
the temple or I filled up half my
notebook with caramel ice you know I
edit ated hard I am not perfect
meditator but I tried so it's good thing
you did in the last few weeks
so this is not confession time this is
not for powers time don't have to talk
about things you didn't do so well but
this is the time this last meditation
together is the time to do what mark
billeted in the diamond color sutra and
he offered his practice such as it is
the best he could do and he made this
highest offering to his teachers so one
by was think about the things you did
all the work you get here think of each
meditation each walk each mantra each
class and through what a beautiful thing
you did and how happy you made the
Buddha and your teachers and give them
this offering so it's important to think
about each thing you did
each time you meditated as many as you
can remember and we'll do this for about
ten minutes starting now
no bad thoughts no failure thoughts just
offer all the times you try
then please come back to your breath
check in with your llama before done in
your heart make sure they're still there
you ask them to stay with you especially
if you're traveling home today it's a
long trip
ask your number to protect you to help
you then three long exhales give this
nice comma of this offering to the
Buddha's to all the people in this world
and other worlds
and you can slowly open your big stretch
so if you ask how our Buddha made his
teachers happy it was this offering okay
not not money not flowers dupa right
attempts to be in fact it may be not
successful every time so I'm going to
try to end on time because I know you
have to catch buses and trains and some
people probably riding wild pig to
Tucson I forgot to talk about the
photograph the last one meditation a
teen who can tell me why it was
difficult to find that photograph you
got it Nick 18 yeah happy pain okay
took me a long time to find it okay she
has a headache why she purified her
camera by studying diamond coasted and
she's happy I'm so happy with my
headache okay
difficulties find this photograph okay
so don't forget when you see the
photograph she has a headache but she's
really happy she cleaned away a lot of
bad karma okay
I know watching has on a risk but it
looks a little bit like mala so that's
like bonus all right
meditation 19 and we have to finish in
20 up to 23 today yeah here we go
Geshe Michael don't talk too much okay
it says how to please a billion Buddhist
all right because in this section which
is 97 if you're following 97 guess not
while you're skipping some sections
combination are sort of does okay he I'm
giving you the main sections that come
lishchyna likes to he has something to
say
and the other sections are not always
there we could do the whole thing slowly
but it would take a couple years these
are the main ideas have come lashus
okay so section ninety-seven sibility I
see this with my powers of clairvoyance
in days long past over the course of
countless eons that are themselves even
more than uncountable far beyond the
time even before the time of the one
gone thus the destroyer of the foe the
perfect and totally enlightened one may
maker of light what Penta grounded he
just honor any anybody have a guess what
tent exalted he dishonored no he he
didn't speak his Lamas name he didn't
say hey Mike or something he said one
god must disturb the whole the perfect
one
the turning lightwind my teacher dupont
guard are okay like you're supposed to
respectfully refer to your Lamas name
okay before that came eighty eight
hundred and forty billion billion
Buddhist I was able to please all of
them and I didn't upset any of them
which is an achievement if you are
student okay okay all right
first of all you have to know well
what offering was he making how did he
make his llamas happy Buddha right
eighty eight hundred and forty billion
billion llamas he made them happy by
offering them not primarily material
things but offering them his practice
his attempt to practice okay
his attempt to practice because this is
the sweetest offering okay then secondly
why it's Lord but I talking about
himself can you guess why is he saying
I collected good karma for eight hundred
forty billion billion teachers you know
huh no it's not that
nope
what do you think's coming there yeah
good good Scott got it next he's going
to say but I didn't make any good karma
compared to the people in the last five
hundred years who study the king hunting
all the Karma I made eight hundred forty
billion billion lamas offered them my
practice is nothing compared to the
karma you are making them okay who said
that
Buddha all right he said all that karma
I made nothing then he he says I'll give
you a comparison come logistics I'll
give you a comparison measure take a
razor blade turn it on end look down the
sharp look on the sharp edge okay how
thick is it okay and compare that to
Mount Everest the biggest mountain in
the world you know he says I don't know
take pretenders a razor blade okay take
a razor blade
look at the sharp sign and compare that
to Mount Everest this is the Karma I
made in
840 billion billion teachers and Mount
Everest is the Karma you guys are making
right now
by studying diamond cutter Sutra that's
comparison okay
that scum listener started me tried to
teach me Chinese medicine she failed but
she tried we did for two years I and she
taught me
chin chin chin did this month soon yeah
miss measurement okay in the old time
Buddhist time we just have this measure
you know you know how many turns your
name or okay now it's smaller than that
razor blades the edge of a razor blades
okay compared to the mountain
compared to biggest mountain okay
there's no way to measure the razor
blade in the old days they don't have
tools that can measure okay then but
it's gonna say pretty soon he's going to
say who cook look at much as him okay
there's no comparison okay
the Karma he made with eight hundred
forty billion billion teachers and the
Karma you are making right now there's
no comparison who decide there's no
comparison only Buddha Kingdom because
really there's no comparison human being
cannot measure the difference okay then
what will happen to you if you try
cuckoo in English we say cuckoo you will
go crazy huh okay if you try to measure
the difference between Buddhist karma
and your karma
if you seriously try to think about it
you'll go crazy Buddha says please don't
try only I can do it trust me trust me
I'm the razor blade you're a Mount
Everest okay trust me don't even try to
compare because if you really tried
you would go crazy he uses the word
crazy no neopor no no Burmese in English
we go like this
it means this person is crazy cuckoo we
call cuckoo crazy what happened to you I
try to compare with his guarantee my god
then I'm agreeing mine's too big okay -
too big got it cool I like him Buddha
can be funny sometimes
then master karma Sheila likes to say he
loved this word the inconceivable result
has to come from an inconceivable cause
he keeps repeating that some Kimi kept a
table some kimmykak eunuch -
inconceivable result Buddhahood must
come from a cause which is also
inconceivable you can't even think about
it okay so Buddha Buddhahood is
inconceivably cruel therefore the cost
that makes it must also be inconceivably
cool okay
he likes that expression then he keeps
trying to find a comparison in the
natural world and Kamala Sheila uses a
Nia grow the tree
okay Nia Grodin it's a special tree in
India we have one here in Diamond
Mountain Cat planted and it's a fig fig
tree
right in your old house here you can go
see how big was it when you started like
this this tall now it's really big
it makes for lots of friends okay
she planted it this thing and and now
it's very very big okay the Buddha used
to like to teach in shrawasti in two
places one is the gardens of jetavana
and one is in the fig tree garden
yeah grow the garden and he taught the
story of what which he studied last week
but that was a long time ago the Pearl
lady he told the story of the Pearl lady
in the fig tree garden okay he liked to
different Gardens in Chaves tree if you
have a chance you should go there the
jetavana garden is still there very very
very very very beautiful okay and you
can get good diarrhea there also well
it's it's worth it
we don't have to have all this health
food okay in in the picture I put a
mustard seed okay this is a famous
biological comparison dr. Stone's nose
that was used by Jesus okay so he'd like
to say that karma is this big sit on
your finger mustard we used it in the
fire small yellow seed and it makes
these huge fields okay a few seeds would
make these huge fields many animals can
live in those fields
so Jesus used to use a mustard seed the
kingdom of heaven is like to a grain of
mustard seed which a man took and sowed
in his field which indeed is the least
of all seeds but when it has grown it is
the greatest and become as a tree and
the birds of the air come and lodge in
the branches so it men commonly Sheila
likes to talk about what the heck is
inside that seed
you know is it a pit fig pit cat it's a
pit right no tiny little seeds in the
fig okay then come on Sheila
I think he is to sit there with these no
Susan see what the heck's inside you
know what makes this seeds so much more
powerful than other seeds you know there
must be something in the core of the
seed there's got to be some big thing
deep down in mustard seed or in a fig
tree seed okay something super powerful
seed okay all right so Carla's like all
Karma's like that you you make someone a
cup of tea you'll have tea for 1,000
lifetimes it's a good investment
okay so do if you get a chance long rim
said if you get a chance to do little
good commerce don't don't pass it by do
it if you have chance to open the door
for somebody or give a chance to wash
one cup in the diamond mountain kitchen
then take the chance okay I wash dishes
for rivet eight for eight years I'd
sometimes I'm so happy I don't have to
wash dishes for a long time
[Music]
all right I was the cook for eight you
know it's I was the worst cook I don't
know if that's a good time or a bad time
okay all right
meditation number 20 now listen okay
here's the next section what number is
that
I'm going to call it 101 okay I'm going
to go to 101 and then the booty said to
Buddha Oh Buddha what about people who
have entered into the way of the
Bodhisattva how should they live how
should they practice how should they
keep their sauce well he already asked
that question that was the first thing
that happened in the Sutra all right so
maybe somebody copied the first place
over by accident they were listening to
rock and roll and they copied the wrong
person okay he asked the same in this
part of the future that we're going to
do now he asked the same question again
101.1 oh one then if you study the
answer that Buddha gives he doesn't talk
about the three parts of the question he
talks about the first the opening of the
question what's the opening of the
question suburi says what about people
who are trying to be Bodhisattvas okay
who have entered the path of
everybody in this room we are trying to
be Bodhisattvas okay we tried to start
Bodhisattva path how should we then how
should we practice how should we think
but the question begins with what about
us people who trying to be Bodhisattvas
okay then Buddha says Buddha goes to the
first part of the question okay before
he went to the second part of Christ now
I go so first what do you mean entered
the bloody son what are you talking
about entered the Bodhisattva path who
who entered the bloody time that's what
his answer okay he's not like oh here's
how you should practice here's how you
should military he says he attacks the
Bernese what what the hell you mean who
entered the Bodhisattva path who do you
think in its abundance I prepare all
right then he says if you think you
entered the Bodhisattva path do it you
got kicked out but he's not passed it
got in that's his answer if you think
you and entered if you think Tina
entered the buddies on the path then
Tina got kicked out of every time okay
what's it mean when you give me an
answer in this class to say it's like
the second husband is nice it's like the
husband okay if you think the husband is
coming from the husband you made a
mistake if you think you are coming from
any place except your sins if you think
someone who's not coming from seeds
could enter the Bodhisattva path you
already got kicked out of that path okay
everything about you is coming from
seeds your hair your eyes your nose your
own thoughts are breaking out of seeds
every second this class is coming out of
your seat okay your trip home comes out
of your seats everything about you is
coming out of your seats if you don't
think that way you what do you mean you
everybody's out now get out of here
okay good it's pretty tough here all all
of my success in my practice all of my
attempts to be a bodhisattva come from
sharing with other people what I
understand okay it all comes from that
and my lamas blessing those two things
okay
it all comes from that okay everything I
am consumed that okay who entered the
body self-repair my sharing with other
people entered the body some time got it
it's cool all right and if it wasn't
that way
I I would never have got my prediction
okay and we talked about it before
there's a stage in your spiritual life
when the buddha there's a funny thing
they put their foot on your head and
they say I predict you're going to be a
Buddha in sixteen months three days and
four hours okay make a mark on your cell
phone you know okay they make a
prediction again if if I thought I was a
buddy suffer and at the past Britta
would not have given me my prediction
okay but I did okay got it
he's going to say that later all right
now last thing here and I'm trying to
move you know I'm not crazy pounce but
I'm trying to get it done so you can say
I finished Comus history Camila Sheila
says did you notice they repeated
something from before Denny Hamlin
Sheila says that's for all the people
who didn't get it the first time okay at
this time and displace 101 he says this
is for all the people who didn't get it
the first time doughnut debater comes
this is Buddhist custom cutting somebody
comes and commonly Sheila let's somebody
come and
sighs Commissioner they said what do you
mean he repeated it for people who
didn't get it the first time
comer says no problem mayor wente this
is some people very sick feeling about
the husband you know must be coming from
the husband you know they here one time
two times three times ten times ten ten
ten ten ten then they go home and fight
with their husband first day sick mind
we ended - in English you say wood wood
head move yeah then you have to repeat
accomplishes some people would head you
know you have to say it again same part
then the other guy says this is
ridiculous if Buddha has repeated every
time for someone who didn't get it this
suitor will never end there's always
someone who doesn't get then the second
time someone doesn't get items then this
soup is going to ask this question
10,000 times the suitor will never end I
have to come to die amount like ten
thousand times you know not so bad and
then he says no no no don't forget you
know it's a powerful antidote powerful
antidote emptiness is powerful everybody
gets its in remainer he says don't worry
it's not endless okay a lot of people
change the first time a lot of people
change the second time it's okay to
repeat a teaching okay it's all right
every time you repeat is valuable it's
precious
then come lishchyna says and if if your
students didn't all get it and you have
to repeat it again but you're tired of
repeating it and you say that's enough
then you are lazy son of a gun
you are lazy slot slot in English means
super lazy you are super lazy you're not
a good teacher can see Michael don't
complain you have to repeat the four
steps four million times you know
somebody will get it who didn't get it
before
and if you don't repeat it you you are
lazy you know you are just lazy person
come on you're like those people who
don't like to wash the dishes okay
teaching is not all fun sometimes you
have to repeat again and again and again
and it's okay somebody told me I should
keep a tape recorder in this Buddha made
this shirt with a special pocket I
always wonder why Buddha made this
pocket now I know I should put a little
tape recorder here you know little
circus what can I do I think use the
first step number one number two all
right okay that's that one now we
reached number 16 of the 18th sections
okay number 16 of the 18th sections this
is about making effort to get more
teaching making effort to get more
teaching okay and it starts business
combination this division it starts with
I think standing me when we do the
fourth one and we have all of them in
one book let's put all the sections of
coalitional also okay give us something
to do when we get old
okay now next picture what is it huh
yeah it's the movie called The Matrix
you should see that movie it's a great
movie it's all about emptiness okay it's
all about world is coming from you and
the stars Keanu Reeves I had to lose a
painting because it's illegal to use his
photograph so I found a painting it
looks just like a photograph and in this
part of the movie
somebody should gun at him boom boom
boom
then he realized everything comes from
me then he just collected and the
bullets for them okay because he
understands everything's coming from him
so me and Scott we like this movie I
think Scott it's a screensaver I think
or used to be so for me this this part
of the movie is a great teaching okay
but it's faint it's just an actor he's
just a movie you know probably someone
threw the ball and it fell down and they
took a photo and you know you know the
whole thing is fake he's not really
special person he's just some Hollywood
guy you know he they paid him some money
to stand up there go like this he just
pretend to be spiritually he got paid to
be spiritual for if you are you know I I
don't know what his personal life but
okay he's it's all fake the whole movie
is fake right I don't know I doubt it
but we don't know it was all filmed in a
really boring place called Reseda and
you know little boy houses and okay
there's one special studio okay it's all
okay but it helps us the movie is fake
but it helps us say young duck Coons Oh
young doc Coons own helpful fake helpful
thing corrects a real thing okay we
talked about it before the opposite is
called Lopez Kunsan say low pay
Krenzel wrong fake fake
Jagga but bad one
how's it done but by the Hydra Jedi I
think good how the Giada and hydrogen
Java Java okay good thing and bad thing
okay that movie is good thing now I'll
tell you something interesting all the
real stuff gender all the real things
like emptiness they come from good fakes
why the body of a Buddha Dharma Claire
highest body of a Buddha is creating by
the wisdom of a Buddha and the wisdom of
a Buddha is fake okay looks like coming
from Buddha really coming from you but
it's a nice fake it's like a movie
matrix okay when you think about
Buddhist mind you are always having
wrong idea it's like husband you think
it coming from Buddha but coming from
you okay so it's fake it looks sick fake
means trick you oh look I'm a wisdom of
Buddha ah you're my CI and you try to
take me I know who you
you can for me just like my husband I
practice my husband many years Buddhist
easy you come for me okay so that's
called the best fake there is okay young
dog Kentucky jokes highest kind of good
things is Buddhist wisdom okay what's
the highest body of Buddha emptiness
body where does it come from
wisdom highest body the Buddha is real
highest body of Buddha which is real
comes from fake wisdom of Buddha then ,
she is like that's so weird
that's amazing you know the coolest fake
thing in the world is Buddhist wisdom
and it creates a Dharma body which is
the only real thing
Wow that's cool okay got it
that's why I put pure deception okay
improbable source means the wisdom of
Buddha you won't guess something which
is fake
creates the ultimate body of a Buddha
okay like caramel a Sheila thinks that's
so weird
you know the best fake thing in the
world makes the only real thing in the
world
okay got it if you have wisdom you will
have a Dumber body if you have a Dumber
body it's a pure okay
it's it's real it's ultimately okay does
it exist ultimately no ah
all right that's another question and by
the way the famous example of these two
kinds of sake is dream and your real
life okay dream if you think about it
James also coming from seeds in your
mind but it's not true it's not real you
know you can die in a dream and you wake
up but if you die in in the real life
you die but both are coming from you
seeds both are equal coming from the
seeds
okay so there's fake real and real real
sorry
real fake and not real thing
okay you got to get used to this and I
like last day because I can go on
without explaining everything clearly
everyone's confused I don't care I don't
have to repeat it meditation we got two
more to go we're on schedule
meditation 22 illusions are illusions
the reason reality is deceptive then he
quotes comma Sheila clogs a Sutra the
sutras are not bad Seamus and I went and
found this for you he doesn't say where
he quoted it from but I found it due to
John Brady's kindness and it says all
things are the Buddha's those who live
in this world are acting out their lives
in things which don't exist okay let's
do the second part it's easier those who
live in this world are acting out their
lives
in things which don't exist this future
by the way if you care is called an
exalted Sutra of the greater way
entitled the shining jewel of the wisdom
of the Buddha's which reaches all things
Arya
Salva Buddha vishaya avataras jnana a
Luca alum Karan a Mahayana sutras okay
good at Tony let's do the second part is
easy those who live in this world are
acting out their lives and things which
don't exist when you get angry at your
husband because he came home and yelled
at you and you didn't even do anything
yet you just open the door and he
started yelling okay again that husband
who yell at you for no reason doesn't
exist there's no such thing as for no
reason there's always a reason you
created every irritating people person
you know it's a diamond mountain junk
okay some student here is kind of
irritating then they will say okay yeah
it's so weird everybody around me to
fool then we're like the world is a
mirror honey the world is a mirror okay
what you see around you is what you are
okay okay
so if you don't understand that you are
living in things which don't exist you
are married to someone who doesn't exist
your whole life okay Gani okay that's
the first part now he says all things
are buna the florist Buddha the lightest
Buddha the cell phone is Buddha okay
everything is pune what it means
the main quality of buddha that they are
talking about right now here is the
wisdom of the Buddha okay which is the
improbable unexpected cause of Dumber
kind of reality buddy
the ultimate something which is fake is
going to create for you your ultimate
body okay but when people look at the
Buddha they feel the same way they feel
about their husband Oh coming from him
not coming so I didn't make Buddha I
wasn't even alive
I'm not battled I'm not bad on so
there's a quality even about a Buddha
that he's not what he seems to be he
looks like he's coming from his time
like a pen but really coming from me now
how many things are like that everything
therefore everything is Buddha okay
that's that's what Buddha staying here
got it everything's checking you
especially husband okay looks like
coming for his name but actually coming
from here Buddha also same and all
things are the same as a Buddha so
therefore all things are Buddha got it
all things are better why because
they're fake nice thing don't think okay
all right you can think about that on
the plane my my boss used to say are you
can sleep on the plane
alright
even enlightenment is illusory now you
want to go deeper if you understood what
I just said and you think about your
understanding that I just talked about
you are probably thinking that that
understanding is coming from its own
side okay cuz it's a have it it's a it's
a disease it's in every part of our
bones we can't even think about
understanding without thinking that the
understanding comes from its own side
okay so when you think about your
understanding oh yes I understand what
you said
everything's Buddha yeah why did you
understand it
oh I'm smart not that you helped other
people understand okay so understand the
seeds of your own understanding then yes
superbunny something then your real body
something because it then it's difficult
to lose your understanding okay if you
don't plant new seeds to understand
you'll get tired of Jing continue say
okay guess not three times ignore us I
got bit by enough bugs for my whole life
and that mountain I don't need to come
again you know you will live your seeds
to want to know okay so you have to keep
planting them if you use g19 to make
money some of the money you make you
should recycle recycle reinvest helps
someone else okay not all of it okay
go to the mall buy yourself some nice
clothes and give some of it to other
people
it's okay it's you're not mustardseed
make big tree okay that's okay but you
have to do that with your understanding
or else some day you will get bored by
this stuff you'll say that's enough I
don't have to go anymore okay
because your seed wore out so you don't
have choice you have to share this with
other people you don't have a choice if
you want to make yourself stupid
don't share with other people okay if
that's your goal for me I want to I want
to reach the place where I don't care
about Jim country okay
don't share don't share with other
people okay good all right we got one
more to go last meditation so talk to
Melissa okay and after the program and I
adopted one right and I you know it just
comes down to my credit car and it
doesn't hurt so much I don't even see it
it goes direct to Diamond Mountain you
know the credit card company winds at me
it's okay make it automatic and you
don't have to think about it okay
all right last meditation oh by the way
the picture 422 which girl is real which
girl is real which is the real one good
look up past the examination
none of them that's the idea
all right last meditation this one I
like because it's a fat cooked and
probably we went to Connie's dinner by
the way
I remind you eight o'clock tonight if
you're still here there'll be a small
quiet responsible dance party here at
eight o'clock in this temple if you if
you have time everybody welcome to come
all right some person told me British
shouldn't dance but I said I don't care
if you're happy you should dance okay
okay it's not a bad thing okay it's a
nice thing right very and as a dancer
she knows
all right it's a way to thank Buddha
okay no problem all right now from
meditation number 23
Carla Sheila talks about two kinds of
wisdom he says from diamond cutter
Souter you'll get two kinds of wisdom
the first is called the wisdom of the
family the wisdom of the family okay
Kamla Sheela calls it the wisdom of the
family and he says it means when you
reach that best fate which is what what
that's a long time ago with the mbuna
when you reach the best non ultimate
thing okay which is wisdom of a bruna
because of that wisdom you join a new
family called the Buddha's okay they're
gonna call you Venable Gelson Buddha
okay you change your last name okay
penny Buddha like that
Jenny Buddha okay they will change your
last name you join a new family and it
means you got confirmed in a new family
okay calmly she knows us and like all
people who just got born you get a body
okay with the wisdom comes to other
bodies of the Buddha so this is called
the wisdom of joining the family means
you were just born into a new family and
you get a new bunny and that's the four
bodies of Buddha
okay okay that's the first one second
one you'll get the wisdom that
understands that all things are equal
it's called yummylicious summit Donna
Summer thousand
the wisdom that all things are equal it
means all things are empty equally the
floor isn't coming from itself the
carpet isn't coming from itself the Sun
is not coming from itself the last
breath you took is not coming from
itself they're all coming from how you
treated other people okay then Camila
Sheila says when we get that second kind
of wisdom you get a bigger family
okay it's called every living being okay
then
SEC first wisdom gets you a new family
all the Buddha's second list will get
you a bigger family all people all
beings all living things everywhere all
worlds okay why are we talking about
this because section one zero seven one
or seven very short Buddha says OSA
bootie think about a person whose body
God bigger that's all he doesn't say
anything else think about a person whose
body got bigger that's why I chose this
photograph his tummy got bigger okay all
right his stomach just got bigger but
when you start to understand diamond
cutter Sutra how big does your body get
as big as everybody as big as you are
really fast
sejong how hey tompa super fat why look
bodies big as the whole world okay last
thing i'll take you to a diamond
DCI way okay I'll teach you to your DCI
way you know this one Stanley loop did
it with you your town you know how many
your counts here that's that's a pity
you should always keep your house donuts
there's no time
it's okay let's pretend this had on it
okay okay pretend Mister Donut
okay here's how we teach it in DC I I
really encourage people who are teaching
ACI to come to DCI programs or listen to
the videos okay then you can learn to
explain things in a way that 7000 people
will come into the seven okay here we go
so I say in my video and it did the same
no and I said why they said well
geshe-la
she's over there and you're over there
so you are not Vivian I mean it sounds
nice
hippie new-age spiritual Oh everything's
one i'm viviane you know not the same as
Binion okay we didn't say it that way I
am Vivian not the same same is different
oh I like you the same as I like him
yeah but that's not the same thing okay
we're not the same we are one yeah one
person they say no no no she's sitting
on the floor you're sitting up there she
has all her hair you don't ya a
different person
okay like that I say okay I agree
visually visually I agree she's over
there I'm over here I
but now let's talk functionally are we
one person functionally okay well what's
getting Michael's favorite thing except
for diamond cutter Sutra is a doughnut
it's very close competition donut donut
or if I drop both in the toilet I think
I wish for the doughnuts so there's a
donut okay now I want more donuts okay
that's my goal for me and every other
month I want just let go has more done
is everyone okay okay that's my goal
okay why I like them okay now comes the
important part because I studied King
contain diamond cutter Souter I
understand that if I want to guarantee
my future supply of donuts okay and if I
only got one today if I got one donut
today okay should I put it in this mouth
or should I put it in her mouth
good okay that's that's our business
people ask me on the plane what's your
business I'm like I'm a Madonna business
all right what do you do I said well I
increase them how do you think if I want
more Donuts to go into this round
players I have to put more Donuts into
that round place okay that's all
according to our business it's our
business called Buddhism right so and
I'd now listen it's nice to give Vivian
doughnut it's a good thing it's very
kind it's very noble
it's very unselfish it's a very
spiritual
to give away your things is that my
motivation no I just want more dunnage
okay
why are you getting the donut because I
want them I like them they okay it's
called enlightened self-interest
I want more donut so I have to give to
her I don't have choice
okay so watch the only way to get a
donut to go into this mouth I have to
put a doughnut into that mouth to get it
doughnut into this mouth okay what okay
so functionally it's her mouth different
from my mouth no if you say mouth it's
not similar it's not like my mouth it is
my mouth okay
it is my mouth okay so we are really one
we are really one thing we're going to
change our name to mimic all rhythm
rhythm rhythm achill okay we're going to
change our name to get you give them a
call okay okay that's the first thing
and by the way all beings in this world
thinking wrong way all of all the people
in this room if you if you're not a
Buddha you are thinking wrong way okay
so therefore all languages are broken
all languages are wrong insufficient
okay there's no word for me you not me
Oh me you you mean we don't have this
one okay who's having donuts today
geshe-la villa michael me you
guess he didn't my Camille is having
donut okay we putting donut into ma our
mouth mouth I'm out mama mama okay so
how how come but I can't talk to us
their language is strange me you guess
you didn't Michael gonna put donut into
mama all the way we just broken okay
when we become better you want your
thinking in the words that we use
because they are broken okay that's a
sign when you learn sounds good you have
to learn singular plural it's worth them
no Russian is worth you're right she's
more more tenses more verb tenses more
persons you know it's all complicated
okay you have to remember how to say I
want you want we want okay it better
languages just give them Michael
me you don't know don't know it in my
mouth
and something like that okay all right
okay that's maybe that's why they don't
talk to us much there's no word for that
okay
I'll answer there's two P but questions
are I will answer hang on let me finish
this first therefore that's why Buddha
said okay you're you are gonna get a
bigger body and maybe you are always
part of a bigger body and we didn't know
it okay maybe you had seven billion
mouths but you didn't know it okay but
now that you have wisdom of Buddha you
are born in a new family and you really
appreciate that it's true that your body
is 7 billion bodies big you're not just
fat you're
hug the tongue okay yes super fun now
you have to buy new pants 14 billion
legs alright last thing you tell me come
on Sheila says one last thing then I'll
answer the two questions okay Carla
Sheila says one last thing he says if
you understand on the last day in the
last five minutes
in the camera Sheila three the last
meditation you finally understand oh I'm
a seven billion people I am seven
billion people they're all good awesome
we're all buna I am seven billion people
don't ever say I understand oh I got it
I got it
I understand nobody else in the room but
I got it okay why put out okay respond
to class okay
come back next year start over okay okay
if you have the wrong idea about why did
you understand this idea about the two
mouths because you shared you shared
what you understood with other people
okay so never forget that seeds for
understanding if you forget then you get
kicked out of understanding and next
week you don't remember okay I'm
finished we're gonna have two quick
questions because people would like to
go home on time sadaqa me was the first
waited just the question had a baby son
his first Susan in explaining the give
the donut to get a donut my students
have said well if every time you get a
donut you give that donut away in order
to get more donut so you never actually
get to eat a donut
it's a good question if I always give
away the tone and I got to get more
doughnuts I'll never get more doughnuts
because I'm less giving the way I the
one I got people give you a hundred
doughnut two people will give you $100
and then then there'll only be two
people you get 98 okay it will happen
like that honestly the money for example
that you can will do much more than you
can ever use even if you wanted to be
selfish you wouldn't need it and you
just give it
Elisabetta nikrif Oh No
thank you for your leadership Esther so
if we are the same when I think that by
eating a doughnut I'm also eating vegan
I like that one I support your school if
I million that I can just meet my
doughnut myself and she lost again there
was an idea in in Buddhism come and eat
the meat right you guys know the story
there was a family with starving and
they had one last piece of food and the
father understood that if he split it
with all the family they will all die in
the next day then he thought if I eat
all the food I can go look for more food
so there is this idea in Buddhism that
sometimes look and spend resources on
yourself like to go to London between
instead of giving away that money
immediately you can make an investment
in yourself because you know it will
help other people later you are just
making an investment in yourself so you
can be a better person
and help my people so that's okay that
part's okay but I think generally for
karma to work that there it has to be
there has to somehow be a wrong
supposition that you are separate from
me okay so - on that - on that yeah
last question miss Thailand miss
Thailand
by the way judgment in charge of
Thailand in December if you're tired of
the desert and you would rather learn
wisdom on the beach both are beautiful
but talk to her about December
especially if you're from cold country
like Germany or Guadalajara Mexico yard
the same ring okay then come to Thailand
a lot of Europeans came last time a lot
of Russians and I guess I didn't know
about Russians really like Thai - so
even there were a couple of guys there
who didn't know there was a program that
they read the diamond cutter and they
crashed the program okay Thank You
Krishna the last future in Kamalesh
Allah - that car you know that's hard
you say come on she lets say the Russian
is changing no yeah you can say that
cheating is wrong sir Chintan is rantin
actually the chintan you told us that's
the first picture how usually our mother
gave that to us about the car the first
yeah and but actually actually there's
no first okay there's no first one
because even if your mother
Tainted to you you wouldn't understand
unless she did it unless you had a seed
from your past life and the Russian is a
car yeah that's the car I am the example
of one car so what do you mean Ronson is
cheating is that mean they all of these
car are coming from seeds if we haven't
got a transportation we serve the others
you will lose all of this see now even
the ruction
and the season all we're gone we will we
haven't got any image of the car and we
haven't got a car in our reality life
yeah is that mean asked me not yeah if
we don't help other people get to Tucson
if we ignore other people's need to go
somewhere then we will lose not just our
own car but the third flower says you'll
lose cars in your country or your city
or yeah even the picture of people
supposed to be the Dharma also go will
go like that
people will forget first people start
practising then people forget what the
books are and then later no more books
and then there's no Dharma door really
bad planets where there's no Dharma no
pigeon but on the other side can we say
that there to come come Kenyon there are
two concepts because ransom is the car I
have now and I would change my camera
maybe a few years after yeah I will I
always have some new car image there's
no picture you can send it will cover
the whole picture okay at this side they
are different and it's useful to think
about even though the ranks and
Institute's and it's useful to think
about them as different sometimes
you know I made karma and therefore I
have a car
thank you yeah all right I got past the
toughest questions let's do a really
nice mandala and dedication and thank
you for coming thank you for asking me
to teach I really enjoyed this it's
really fun for me this is the most fun I
have all year to teach something deep to
have people who want to learn something
deep it's very unusual and I'm very
grateful that you came from many places
and thanks for letting me teach and I
really enjoy it and I hope we can do
come let's you know for together okay